<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Working On... on Nico Stern</title><link>https://nicostern.de/categories/working-on.../</link><description>Recent content in Working On... on Nico Stern</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nicostern.de/categories/working-on.../index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Star Vault</title><link>https://nicostern.de/p/star-vault/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 04:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nicostern.de/p/star-vault/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://nicostern.de/p/star-vault/obsidian-graph-scr.png" alt="Featured image of post Star Vault" />&lt;p>On &lt;a class="link" href="https://starvault.nicostern.de" target="_blank" rel="noopener"
>starvault.nicostern.de&lt;/a> I continuously update Obsidian templates and structural ideas on how to elevate Obsidian to an intelligent, automated knowledge vault using a node.js-based Quartz server instance for show casing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I learned to love Obsidian&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>.md&lt;/code> only(*) approach combined with the &lt;em>infinite&lt;/em> possibilities provided by the comunity through plugings (view my own: &lt;a class="link" href="nicostern.de/p/todoian/" >Todoian&lt;/a>), Obsidian became my smart journal, habit tracker, project manager and overall second brain - &amp;lsquo;cause remember:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>&amp;ldquo;Your mind is for having ideas, not for holding them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong> &lt;br>
David Allen, &lt;em>Getting Things Done&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Main content in StarVault:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;code>smart templates&lt;/code> adapting to note titles and thus making Obsidian a structured, linked place (using Templater)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;code>naming, prefix, tagging and yaml conventions&lt;/code> I gathered throughout years of evelating my Obsidian usage combining many and many of tutorials&lt;/li>
&lt;li>thinking in Obsidian&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>CheckMathe</title><link>https://nicostern.de/p/checkmathe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nicostern.de/p/checkmathe/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://nicostern.de/p/checkmathe/cover-creamy.jpg" alt="Featured image of post CheckMathe" />&lt;p>Visit website on [http://checkmathe.de].
TODO: Download in the App Store.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While still in the process of building the app, checkmathe.de is my vision of students and teachers coming together and start learning with the overhead of getting started converging to 0.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On the website, new students will be able to search for teachers by &lt;em>CheckMather&lt;/em>, an approach where students filter potential teachers by their expertise.
Students will also be able to book recurring tutorings or &lt;em>InstantCheck&lt;/em>s where we promise to provide a teacher within less than 7 days for emergencies - again filtered by the perfect teacher&amp;rsquo;s knowledge.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the iOS (and maybe Android sometimes&amp;hellip;) App, students will be able to view their last tutorings and to have quick access to tutoring materials like PDFs from their teachers. They will be able to book tutorings from anywhere and view pending payments. My dream would be an Apple Pay integration where students can pay on the fly.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stay tuned for updates :).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Todoian</title><link>https://nicostern.de/p/todoian/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 02:32:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nicostern.de/p/todoian/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://nicostern.de/p/todoian/cover-rainbow.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Todoian" />&lt;p>Nothing to look at to this point since not finished. &lt;br>
As of now, the plugin is supposed to fetch tasks in Todoist marked as &amp;ldquo;Top 3 for today&amp;rdquo; and to display them in Obsidian. Or maybe to import them to not be dependent on Todoist in future.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>